

Daniel Ruszel

Data Engineer

♀ 1665 Buenos Aires, Argentina ⋈ danirusz@gmail.com 📞 +54 9 11-6464-1956 🔞 Married

13/07/1989 in ruszeldaniel

Profile

I have 8 years' experience in the banking sector and more than 10 years of experience in Business Intelligence projects.

I consider myself a proactive person, I'm always trying to find the best technical solution that fit with user's requirement. I know how to manage my time well and I'm goal-oriented person.

Education

2008 - 2016 Buenos Aires, Argentina

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Universidad Católica de Salta

Professional Experience

2021 - present Remote, Argentina Sr. Data Engineer at Credit One Bank

Hexacta

Role: Sr. Data Engineer

Project: As part of the BI Data Development Team we handle all kinds of requirements related to the maintenance of legacy data pipelines and develop new features per user

requirements.

Responsibilities: Build new ETL processes using Microsoft SSDT. Maintain and apply data modeling in our two data repositories (DataLake and Data Warehouse). On-Call

monitoring of SLA processes.

Skills: SSIS, SQL Server, Oracle, JAMS, Service Now, JIRA, GIT.

Methodology: Scrum, Kanban.

Project: Internal Hexacta's projects. Help the H.R department to gather information from internal web surveys related to the work environment and build reports.

Responsibilities: Set and configure a VM ubuntu server. Configure and install our data tools: Docker, GIT, Sybase, and Python libraries. Build simple dags to schedule our

tasks. Python scripting using Pandas library **Skills**: Python, Pandas, Airflow, Docker, GIT.

2013 – 2021 Buenos Aires, Argentina

Sr. Business Intelligence Developer Analyst at Citibank

Charles Taylor

Role: BI - Technical Lead

Project: Treasury Regulatory Reports – TRR (2015-ON GOING). The project consisted of detailed daily regulatory reports required by government entities (like CNBV and Banxico). These reports are highly auditable. We extract the information from different sources like (Teradata/Sybase/Oracle databases), Excel spreadsheets, and plain text files, develop an ETL process to load the information in a data warehouse, and show it with a Microstrategy Report.

Responsibility: Lead a technical team allocated in Mexico. Collaborate with the user to define the business rules. Project planning and effort estimation. Solution design and development. Coaching new members.

Skills: Ab Initio, Teradata, Shell Script, Autosys, JIRA, Service Now, Microstrategy.

Methodology: Waterfall

Project: Citibanamex Semaforos (2013 - 2014). The project consisted in building a data model to analyze and classify credit offers that were made to customers through different channels, the ETL process interacted with different data sources from each channel (home banking, ATM, IVR) and was homologated in a common layout for its exploitation.

Responsibility: ETL Development, Technical liaison with stakeholders and key users, Business requirements analysis, and Production support and implementations for ETL solutions.

Skills: Ab Initio, Java, Autosys, Service Now, Shell Script.

2011 – 2013 Buenos Aires, Argentina

PL/SQL Developer at Telefónica

Everis

Role: Analyst Developer

Project: Corrective and preventive maintenance. (2012-2013)

Responsibility: Business requirement analysis. Analytical query development for

business users. Unit testing.

Skills: PL-SQL, HPS, Shell Scripting, Pro-C, Remedy.

Methodology: Waterfall.

Role: Developer

Project: PFFN (National Telephone Numbering Fundamental Plan) (2011-2012). **Responsibility:** Shell scripting development of automatization process. SQL

development transactional queries.

Incident management in Remedy platform.

Skills: PL-SQL, HPS, Shell Scripting, Pro-C, Remedy.

Methodology: Waterfall.

Skills

SQL PL/SQL	• • • •	Databases Oracle / Teradata / Sql Server/ Sybase	• • • • • • e/DB2
Ab Initio ETL	• • • •	SSIS ETL	••••
MicroStrategy	• • • • •	Airflow <i>Orchestrator</i>	••••
AutoSys	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet		
Orchestrator		Linux Shell Scripting	• • • •
Python	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet		
		MS Office	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet
JIRA	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet		
		Service Now	• • • • •
Agile	\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet		
Scrum / Kanban		GIT	• • • • •